<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Janina Hartley&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <description>Janina Hartley’s ui, web, and graphic design portfolio..
</description>
    <link>http://janinahartleydesigns.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://janinahartleydesigns.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 07:29:04 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 07:29:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fun with colors pt 2</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt; Change in direction &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I came back to the wine cellar picture, and was playing with different typefaces, and one of them, Lakeside, stood out to me, and made me think of a majestic harvest moon. I ended up completely scraping the wine cellar idea and wanted to make an illustration of an august moon setting. I ended up making a super stylized happy moon, using the same three colors, in a barren countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blog-image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog-post-images/harvest-moon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Harvest Moon&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a habit of giving cutesy faces to inanimate objects. I kept playing around with the harvest moon idea, again trying to come up with a setting where I could use this. A promotion for a local moon festival came to mind. Thus I made a little illustration of the moon with a moon festival sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blog-image drop-shadow&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog-post-images/moon-festival.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Moon Festival&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/06/05/fun-with-colors-pt-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/06/05/fun-with-colors-pt-2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fun with colors</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt; Color generators &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the other day someone from Slack posted a link to one of those websites that generates color combinations. This one, Color Calculator, gives you the option to decide what kind of relationship you want the colors to have with each other (complementary, monochromatic, analogous, etc), and I’ve always wanted to try out one of those create-a-design-based-off-of-limited-colors challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just for fun I tried it out. Using a dark red I generated an analogous color combination and opened a new file in Illustrator. Based off that colors I immediately thought of wine and vineyards. I ended up warming up with a little champagne (or rosé) icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blog-image glass-image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog-post-images/glass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wine glass&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to think up a more flushed out design, I thought up a scenario where a local restaurant or wine bar was having a special event. I designed a promotional menu with some featured kinds of wine and snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;blog-image drop-shadow&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog-post-images/wine-poster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wine Poster&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not quite happy with it so far. Looks a little too boxy. I wouldn’t mind some more practice with informational posters and designs. Maybe I’ll make that one of my next side projects…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/06/04/fun-with-colors.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/06/04/fun-with-colors.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seattle Trip</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt; Visiting the Bellevue office &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I got to take a brief, private tour of a local office in Bellevue. Thanks to family connections, I got to see real world UI and UX designers and PMs in action. I also got to see a few wireframes, flowcharts, and mockups of the teams current project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nice being able to see exactly what a UX or UI job would entail in the “real world.” Thanks to The Iron Yard, I have a pretty good level of foundation knowledge for a junior UI or UX job (at this point I”m looking more for UI, possible UI - development). But it’s nice to get a realistic sense of what I might actually be doing in a UI/UX job. It also helps me better prepare for questions that I would want to ask in a interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company, Agilysys, is a leading provider of hospitality software solutions (they design and market POS and PMS systems, as well as many others). The team I got to shadow was working on a new product for kiosk machines that would stand in Grab n Go outlets. Basically, they are creating an interaction that would happen when a customer wants to buy anything from a meal, to a quick snack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to talk with one of the head UX designers, who talked about how one of their biggest challenges is creating a product that would work for a business that has one simple, strict menu, as well as for a business with multiple menus, multiple choices (a burger that has choices of lettuce, cheeses, etc), and combinations. It’s really interesting seeing a team work through different designs, different user stories, and workflows that lead to working prototypes and Beta systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m grateful for being able to see some real world offices, and meet some great designers and developers.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/05/31/seattle-trip.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/05/31/seattle-trip.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Merge Conflicts</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt; It&#39;s like, 2am &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright. So this has happened enough times that I need to write this somewhere so I don’t have to go and keep finding it on the internet. Merge conflicts. You getting a bunch of .scssc file conflicts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delete them: 
&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font bg-font&quot;&gt; git rm [file name] &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;( &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1380670/how-do-i-fix-a-merge-conflict-due-to-removal-of-a-file-in-a-branch&quot;&gt; http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1380670/how-do-i-fix-a-merge-conflict-due-to-removal-of-a-file-in-a-branch &lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about those super fun DS_Store files? Remember the .gitignore stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Show those hidden files: 
&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font bg-font&quot;&gt; defaults write com.apple.finder AppleShowAllFiles YES &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;( &lt;a href=&quot;http://ianlunn.co.uk/articles/quickly-showhide-hidden-files-mac-os-x-mavericks/&quot;&gt; http://ianlunn.co.uk/articles/quickly-showhide-hidden-files-mac-os-x-mavericks/ &lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then delete the DS_Store files: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font bg-font&quot;&gt; find . -name .DS_Store -print0 | xargs -0 git rm -f –ignore-unmatch &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and type “.DS_Store” into the .gitignore file (you may have to create it*): 
&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font bg-font&quot;&gt; git commit -m ‘.DS_Store banished! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*git add .gitignore ( &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/107701/how-can-i-remove-ds-store-files-from-a-git-repository&quot;&gt; http://stackoverflow.com/questions/107701/how-can-i-remove-ds-store-files-from-a-git-repository &lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/05/24/merge-conflicts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/05/24/merge-conflicts.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3D Painting!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt; Look at this! &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw this video on LinkedIn the other day. This is incredible to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe class=&quot;blog-video&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I8OuSJKSkwE?list=PLKfWL8IXgKBte4TfD53pLaHONfSYCX0RH&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be honest, the rate of which technology has grown in my lifetime has sometimes been unnerving (I may, or may not, buy into the whole Skynet thing). But virtual reality is something I’m really excited for, now more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, growing up doodling in sketchbooks every night (without fail), the idea of being able to paint, in 3D is like a dream come true. As a kid, Harold and the Purple Crayon was one of those books that made me wish reality wasn’t so restricting. I thought the idea that drawing something and having it come to life, no strings attached, was incredible. This seems like the closest thing to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; VR filled future &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sort of thing gets me excited for what kind of projects I could be a part of in the future. One of my personal projects is to create a “game” or interaction experience where a child could virtually live through historical events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout my research of different methods of teaching, one of the reoccurring ideas that’s stuck with me is that memory and experience are tied together. We are more likely to remember something when we have some sort of stimuli connected with that memory. The same way the smell of a certain dish may remind us of that vacation we took as a kid. Or the way the color purple always makes us think of that favorite dress we wore to a school dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create an experience for children (students) that would help engage, and educate, through experience, is a dream come true.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/05/22/3D-painting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/05/22/3D-painting.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Client Project</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt; RedArena &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.redarena.org&quot;&gt; RedArena &lt;/a&gt; is a local Dripping Springs organization that offers physical therapy, and traditional therapy, to children and adults while riding horses. Horseback riding is a specialized therapy option that can be extremely beneficial for children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Creating an app for a real client &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nice working with a client for a change. Not that I don’t like personal projects and such, it’s just nice to have someone (who isn’t a designer) look at your work and show you a view you probably wouldn’t have ever saw. Working with another designer was also nice, but it definitely had it’s stresses. I like working with others, but I’m usually worried that I’ll fall behind, or end up having people waiting on me before they can continue. But when someone is better at one thing, and your better at another it makes it easy to split up the workload a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had experience working with clients before, and it really is nice (maybe I’ve just been really lucky). You have (in my experience) enough set rules to start a project, but enough freedom to go off in all sorts of different directions. My hurtles usually come in reigning myself back enough so that I don’t go too far off in one direction just to have the client like an entirely different direction. But working on my portfolio and self brand again is kind of teaching me a little more of that, which is always good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/04/26/client-project.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/04/26/client-project.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mobile App</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt; Recreational sports app &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next project is to design a strictly mobile app for a recreational sports team. I chose to make an app specifically for a swim team (but one that could be used for any sport).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In researching different sports related apps, one thing I find fairly commonplace is the lack of heavy feedback from pressing buttons. Unlike with desktop, there isn’t a lot of place to have fancy effects happening when you click, hover, or swipe a button or page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of them (a lot of iPhone apps in general it seems) usually have nav bars of some sort on the bottom of the screen. But not all; most that don’t have a bottom nav bar will have some sort of drop down or list page that acts as their main navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main goal of the app seems to be to let the manager/coach or player get in and out as fast as possible (like most apps), without being distracted or delayed by fancy animations or unnecessary effects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/04/12/mobile-apps.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/04/12/mobile-apps.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Web App</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt; Designing for an app, not a website &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So last week was my first time designing an app for the web…it was interesting. I had always looked at apps as primarily phone based, and found it interesting that web apps are so much more common then I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Redesigning LinkedIn &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this project, we decided to focus on the LinkedIn Home page. A lot of people have trouble traversing through LinkedIn, or don’t care about what is displayed on the current home page. We each got to choose what kind of user we wanted to design for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my home page, I wanted to mostly simplify what was already there. I was focusing on a user that used LinkedIn as a sort of portal dedicated to aide them in their search for a new job. It wasn’t as highly focused on finding new connections, more about staying in the know with current news (which would be chosen by the user, depending on their personal or career interests), and easily finding new job postings and opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thusly, I wanted the most “in your face” options to be about current job listings, instead of “People you may know.” I also wanted to implement the news side of LinkedIn. If someone is serious about the type of career they want, they need to know current events revolving around it. Lastly, their homepage would show how many people are viewing their profile. That’s, in my opinion, one of the best aspects of LinkedIn right now. You get to see how “popular” you are, and how many people are really looking at you, looking at your skills, and for someone who is looking for a job, that’s really useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/04/05/web-app.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/04/05/web-app.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>jQuery</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt; Re-learning jQuery &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I (re)learned some of the basics of jQuery. It’s a nice change from the Javascript of last week (although, when I have some more free time…, I’d like to do some more Javascript tutorials. See if I can get a better sense of it, and not have to rely on jQuery so much). Mostly been doing some practices, getting back into the flow of things. I’ve got some new CodePens (super hacky right now) of a few of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also went back after a few weeks to redo some old CSS Animations on CodePen. I had lost a few of them (forgot I wasn’t in a program that I could “save as,” and forgot to Fork them…), and it’s been weighing over my shoulder to go back and redo them best I can. At least this time I managed to make them prettier!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt; Getting back into jQuery CodePens; &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font&quot;&gt; 1) &lt;/span&gt; = &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/qZjvGK&quot;&gt; http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/qZjvGK &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font&quot;&gt; 2) &lt;/span&gt; = &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/eZRoWV&quot;&gt; http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/eZRoWV &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font&quot;&gt; 3) &lt;/span&gt; = &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/VaWogw &quot;&gt; http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/VaWogw  &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;
(really more of an extension of #2, but with some bonus content)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt; Redo CSS Animations; &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(the redos)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font&quot;&gt; 3) &lt;/span&gt; = &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/YqxKrp&quot;&gt; http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/YqxKrp &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font&quot;&gt; 4) &lt;/span&gt; = &lt;a href=&quot; http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/JXyPZG&quot;&gt;  http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/JXyPZG &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(the original)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font&quot;&gt; 1) &lt;/span&gt; = &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/EKWdOm&quot;&gt; http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/EKWdOm &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font&quot;&gt; 2) &lt;/span&gt; = &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/oxZQqm&quot;&gt; http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/oxZQqm &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sec-font&quot;&gt; 5) &lt;/span&gt; = &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/aNJPoP&quot;&gt; http://codepen.io/jhartley/pen/aNJPoP &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/03/28/jquery.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/03/28/jquery.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CSS Zen Garden pt 2</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt; CSS Zen Garden &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost done for the weekend on my CSS Zen Garden project. I’m really liking how the header and CSS animations are looking, I’m just a little concerned that it’s all looking too “Dr. Suess-y.” The colors don’t look all that inviting (not that Futurism is necessarily the most “inviting” time in art history). Maybe I’m just worrying too much since I just now realized that my color scheme is exactly the same as my shower curtains (thought it looked familiar!). After this weekend I’m going to be focused on getting the middle sections looking the way I want them to on the largest breakpoint (desktop size). Minus that, I’m really happy with how responsive everything is (or seems to be so far on my screen)!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/03/27/css-zen-garden-pt-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://janinahartleydesigns.com//2016/03/27/css-zen-garden-pt-2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
